Finding Aid for Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.) records, 1920-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.) records
1920-1988
Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.)
85508 Bk.2 2; UBKl
Correspondence, minutes, publications, membership lists, histories, scrapbooks, and photographs relating to club activities, especially state and national conventions, 1921-1966.
6 linear feet
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the organization (donor no. 3608 ) and from Dr. Luella Cable (donor no. 4990 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In the summer of 1921 several business women in Ann Arbor became interested in the National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs and the Michigan Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs. They felt that there were enough women in the area engaged in business or occupying responsible positions to form a local club which would be federated with the state and national organizations. A preliminary meeting with seventy representative women was held. Then in November 1921, the Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor was established.
The record group is divided into the following series: Historical and Background Material; Correspondence and other papers; Meeting Minutes; Membership material; Programs and activities; District and state and national materials; Photographs; and Scrapbooks. There is one folder in the records relating to the organization's work on behalf of better housing in Ann Arbor, 1921-1922.
Subjects:
Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.); Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Historical / Background
  - Chapter histories,,, notes, 1923; 1924; 1929; 1951 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions and By-laws, 1923-1959; 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Annual Officers reports, 1967-1986 (Box 1)
  - Initiation ceremonies (Box 1)
  - Songs (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Tributes and memorials (Box 1)
- Correspondence and other papers, 1920-1984
  - 1920s (Box 1)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - January-March, 1923 (Box 1)
  - April-August, 1923 (Box 1)
  - September-December, 1923 (Box 1)
  - January-September, 1924 (Box 1)
  - October-December, 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1962-1967 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1984 (Box 1)
- Meeting minutes, 1921-1986
  - 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1937 (Box 1)
  - 1946, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
    (include annual reports)
  - 1955-1960 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1962, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1963-1968 (Box 2)
  - 1974-1986 (Box 2)
- Membership material, 1921-1986
  - Membership lists, 1921-1930; 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Membership lists, 1930-1966 (Box 2)
  - Membership lists, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Membership remittance summary and lists (Box 2)
- Programs and activities, 1921-1987
  - Publicity committee, 1921-1924 (Box 2)
  - Local programs, 1926-1930; 1934 (Box 2)
  - Civic participation including material on the Swabian Dance Hall, 1921-1964 (Box 2)
  - Report on Ann Arbor Housing scrapbook, 1921-1922 (Box 2)
  - Education including essay "Value of a College Education for Women", 1923-1929 (Box 2)
  - Good Will Tours, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Civil Defense, 1950-1960 (Box 2)
  - Traffic Safety Conferences, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Political interests, legislation, 1922-1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Programs from Ann Arbor, state and national special events, 1940-1987 (Box 2)
  - Press releases, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
- District and state and national materials, 1921-1967
  - District I correspondence and annual reports, 1931-1934 (Box 2)
  - District II correspondence and annual reports, 1951-1957; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - District IX meeting minutes and annual reports, 1957-1962; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - District IX meeting minutes and annual reports, 1963-1967 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs annual reports and correspondence, 1923-1966; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1921-1962 annual reports, convention proceedings, 1952-1962, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Bulletins of sister Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Washtenaw County Federation of Women's Clubs, 1918-1964 (Box 3)
  - Various publications (Box 3)
- National and State conventions, 1921-1966
  - National convention Cleveland, Ohio, 1921 (Box 3)
  - National convention Chattanooga, Tennessee, 1922 (Box 3)
  - State convention Flint, 1922 (Box 3)
  - National convention Portland, Oregon, 1923 (Box 3)
  - State convention Muskegon, 1923 (Box 3)
  - National convention West Baden, Indiana, 1924 (Box 3)
  - State convention Jackson, 1924 (Box 3)
  - National convention Portland, Maine, 1925; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - State convention Muskegon, 1925 (Box 3)
  - National convention Des Moines, Iowa, 1926 (Box 3)
  - State convention Detroit, 1926 (Box 3)
  - State board meeting Grand Rapids, 1926 (Box 3)
  - National convention Oakland, California, 1927 (Box 3)
  - State conventions, 1927 (Box 3)
  - National conventions New Orleans, Louisiana, 1928 (Box 3)
  - State convention Grand Rapids, 1928 (Box 3)
  - National convention Mackinac Island, Michigan, 1929 (Box 3)
  - National convention Chicago, Illinois, 1930 (Box 4)
  - State convention Flint, 1930 (Box 4)
  - National convention Richmond, Virginia, 1931; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - State convention Marquette, 1931 (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional conference St. Paul, Minnesota, 1932 (Box 4)
  - State convention Kalamazoo, 1932 (Box 4)
  - National convention Chicago, 1933 (Box 4)
  - State convention Detroit, 1933 (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional conference Grand Rapids, Michigan, 1934 (Box 4)
  - National convention Seattle, Washington, 1935 (Box 4)
  - State convention Sault Ste Marie, 1936 (Box 4)
  - National convention Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1937 (Box 4)
  - State convention Detroit, 1938 (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional convention Madison, Wisconsin, 1940 (Box 4)
  - State convention Grand Rapids, 1940 (Box 4)
  - State convention Bay City, 1942 (Box 4)
  - National convention Dallas, Texas, 1963 (Box 4)
  - National convention Washington, D.C., 1965 (Box 4)
  - National convention Atlanta, Georgia, 1966 (Box 4)
- Photographs, 1925-1929; 1972-1986; undated
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 4)
  - Photographs Portland, Maine convention (also UBKl), 1925 (Box 4)
  - Photographs Oakland, California convention, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Photographs Mackinac Island, Michigan convention, 1929 (Box 4)
  - Photograph album: convention and awards photos, 1972-1986 (Box 4)
  - Album, 1973-1985 (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1920s-1980s
  - Various dates, 3 volumes; 1 folders (Box 4)
  - 1920s-1980s, 4 volumes (Box 5)
  - 1920s-1980s, 4 volumes (Box 6)
    (continued)